<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Robin (axcelott)</title>
    <description>Thoughts and opinions of a teenager from the Netherlands.</description>
    <link>https://roblog.nl</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>webmaster@roblog.nl (Robin Boers)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Made with ♡ in the Netherlands. Copying is an act of love. Please copy.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="//roblog.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <!-- INSERT NEW POSTS HERE -->
    <item>
      <title>Stop saying "users" and "content"</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/stupid-terminology</link>
      <pubDate>15 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/stupid-terminology</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Terminology like <em>users</em> and <em>content</em> is demeaning and
        hurtful.
      </p>
      <p>
        Artists aren't creating <em>content</em> to populate our
        datasets--they're creating movies, music, essays, drawings, games,
        paintings. Labeling a work that someone created, out of passion and
        love, <em>content</em>, is frankly disrespectful. It reduces the
        creative work from something beautiful to merely another piece of
        <em>content</em>, and greatly undervalues the effort and skill necessary
        to create it.
      </p>
      <p>
        Likewise, calling people <em>users</em>, dehumanizes them. It turns them
        into a mere datapoint, or worse, an asset to be exploited.
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          There are only two industries that call their customers "users":
          illegal drugs and software.
        </p>

        —<cite>Edward Tufte</cite>
      </blockquote>

      <p>We should stop using these terms; they're stupid.</p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Banning phones is not solving anything</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/symptom-relief</link>
      <pubDate>14 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/symptom-relief</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Terminology like <em>users</em> and <em>content</em> is demeaning and
        hurtful.
      </p>
      <p>
        Artists aren't creating <em>content</em> to populate our
        datasets—they're creating movies, music, essays, drawings, games,
        paintings. Labeling a work that someone created, out of passion and
        love, <em>content</em>, is frankly disrespectful. It reduces the
        creative work from something beautiful to merely another piece of
        <em>content</em>, and greatly undervalues the effort and skill necessary
        to create it.
      </p>
      <p>
        Likewise, calling people <em>users</em>, dehumanizes them. It turns them
        into a mere datapoint, or worse, an asset to be exploited.
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          There are only two industries that call their customers "users":<br />
          illegal drugs and software.
        </p>

        —<cite>Edward Tufte</cite>
      </blockquote>

      <p>
        Terms like these shift focus away from the humans in the equation.
        Language is the lense through which we see the world. Use it wisely.
      </p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the mobile phone ban</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones-banned</link>
      <pubDate>08 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones-banned</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[
      <p>
        Last month the Dutch government announced that from next year on mobile
        phones will be banned in high school. As a student who is currently in
        high school, I think it's a fundamentally good development, but the
        media attention around it just feels wrong.
      </p>

      <p>
        The news is full of items of cherry-picked comments from teenagers who
        feel "relieved" because they "finally talk to each other". But also
        teenagers who are sad because "they won't have any memories of high
        school if they can't take photos". They present a greatly exaggerated
        story praising this measure the government imposed to protect the youth
        against themselves.
      </p>

      <p>
        It's all so over the top. Contrary to popular belief, teenagers
        <em>do</em> talk to each other, even in the presence of a mobile phone.
        In breaks, we play card games like Uno and Bullshit. We read books. We
        complain about how stupid school and homework is. You know, normal
        stuff. And our phones have a place too. Sometimes we play mobile games
        in the break, like
        <a href="//www.evilapples.com" target="_blank">Evil Apples</a> or
        <a href="//garticphone.com/" target="_blank">Gartic Phone</a>. But
        that's still something we do <em>together</em>.
      </p>

      <p>
        And, yes, phones are distracting. Yes, they cause mayhem from time to
        time. Yes, social media is shit. I am very much aware. But all of that
        is also true for adults. These devices and the apps on them are made to
        be extremely addictive, it's their fucking business model. It's not just
        teenagers who get addicted. And it's certainly not our fault that we get
        addicted. Even the people who built these apps in the first place, who
        know exactly how they work and what tricks are used to exploit our
        psychology, they still
        <a href="//thesocialdilemma.com">aren't able to restrain themselves</a>.
        Adults aren't magically immune.
      </p>

      <p>
        It feels like it's a bunch of grey birds going "kids these days...",
        "you can't get off your phones, and now we're going to take them away",
        "it's for your own good!" and then continuing to celebrate on social
        media. Hypocrisy at its peak.
      </p>

      <p>
        So yes, I think it's great that phones have been banned in high schools.
        The next step would be everywhere else (and especially the parlement).
      </p>

      <details>
        <summary>Extras</summary>
        <p>Some other notes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <p>
              Schools spent years digitizing everything. Schedules, grades,
              homework, study materials and more are now all exclusively
              available in web applications. They made this move with the
              assumption that these platforms would always be accessible for
              students via their mobile phone (a wrong assumption by the way,
              because this excludes students like myself that would rather leave
              their phone at home). How are schools going to deal with this?
            </p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>
              How are schools going to enforce this? They've been burdened with
              enough additional administrative tasks already. And what even
              counts as a mobile phone?
              <del
                >Do all mobile devices count? What about my iPad? Or an old iPod
                Touch? My DIY Raspberry Pi Zero project with a rectangular touch
                screen? And what if it were a square instead? And what about
                smartwatches? They can TikTok too. Does every portable device
                with an internet connection fall under this new law?</del
              >
            </p>
            <p>
              <ins
                >Update: I read the law on rijksoverheid.nl and they include
                "smartphones", "tablets", and "smartwatches". <em>However</em>,
                they do not provide a definition for these terms.
                Disappointing.</ins
              >
            </p>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phones, assumptions and expectations</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones</link>
      <pubDate>29 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[
      <p>
        I'm 16 years old. I strongly dislike my phone. You never thought you'd
        ever hear those two sentences from the same person, did you?
      </p>

      <p>
        I started feeling like this a few years back. My parents decided I
        couldn't charge my phone at night, and consequently my phone died a lot
        during the day. After a while, I stopped missing it. Even if I have it
        with me, I don't use it anymore.
        <a href="//blog.geheimesite.nl/2022/03/een-maand-zonder-telefoon.html"
          >Last year, I challenged myself to put away my phone for a month</a
        >, and my primary conclusion was that most inconvience caused by not
        having a phone, is imposed by the expectations and assumptions of other
        people.
      </p>

      <p>
        I hate the fact that I'm expected to always be available for everyone.
        All it takes is one tap: <i>ping</i>. It's annoying. Every time I'm
        trying to actually get something done, my phone just keeps going
        <i>beep boop ping pong</i>. It's like someone is tapping my shoulder
        every few minutes. "Can I have your attention please?" My concentration
        is already severly fractured. I don't want to know that you've tagged
        me, I don't feel like sending selfies back and forth and I don't care
        that some artist released a new album.
        <em>I just want to get my shit done</em>.
      </p>

      <p>
        Phones are supposed to be tools. Tools should never, ever,
        <em>ever</em>, have control over us. We're supposed to be the master of
        our tools, not the other way around.
      </p>

      <p>
        That's easily solved tho. My phone is always on silent. However, people
        still <em>expect</em> me read and reply instantly. That's what bothers
        me: the fucking social pressure to participate.
      </p>

      <p>
        Furthermore, everyone assumes you to have and always carry a phone with
        you. Oh yes,
        <em>let's do a Kahoot</em>! Or some other activity requiring a phone. Or
        <em>just scan this QR code and you'll be done</em>. Or how about we put
        the schedule on a mobile app? You'll need a smartphone to get a DigiD
        too, which is needed to access your medical records, apply for vaccines,
        and pay your taxes. Sooner or later you'll need to setup mobile banking
        as well, because the device we use for signing into the online banking
        portal doesn't have replaceable batteries and we won't give you a
        replacement when it eventually dies.
      </p>

      <p>
        It's the small things, the assumptions and expectations.<br />
        And it's so annoying.
      </p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>