<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Robin (axcelott)</title>
    <description>Thoughts and opinions of a teenager from the Netherlands.</description>
    <link>https://roblog.nl</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>webmaster@roblog.nl (Robin Boers)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Made with ♡ in the Netherlands. Copying is an act of love. Please copy.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="//roblog.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <!-- INSERT NEW POSTS HERE -->
    <item>
      <title>HotFox: RSS superpowers for Firefox</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/hotfox</link>
      <pubDate>20 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/hotfox</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        A few weeks ago, I ran across an old article about XUL, a XML variant
        developed by Mozilla for use in the Firefox interface. They killed it a
        few years ago in favor of HTML, once again leaving behind their
        tried-and-tested solutions in their ever-lasting chase to be as cool and
        hot as Google and its Chromium project. So, to try it out anyway, I
        installed
        <a href="//palemoon.org">Pale Moon</a>, a Firefox fork that has kept the
        traditional XUL interface in its former glory.
      </p>

      <p>
        Part of said traditional interface was a subscribe button that popped up
        in the toolbar while visiting some sites. When clicked, it showed a list
        of all web feeds that the site exposed. By selecting one of them, or by
        simply visiting the feed URL, you got this fancy feed preview with an
        option to subscribe to it with your favorite RSS reader.
      </p>

      <p>
        Why exactly did "modern" browsers remove this? When I visit an RSS feed
        in contemporary Firefox, I get this monstrosity:
      </p>

      <figure>
        <img src="/images/blog/rss-plain.png" alt="A bunch of confusing XML" />
        <figcaption>Ew, that looks disgusting.</figcaption>
      </figure>

      <p>
        Why doesn't the browser give me the ability to subscribe to a feed
        (anymore)?
        <a href="//www.feed.style" target="_blank">
          Why is it left for developers to figure out</a
        >, when it should obviously be the browser's job?
      </p>

      <p>
        In an attempt to right this wrong once and for all, I built HotFox, a
        browser extension. It does two things:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>
          It adds a button to the toolbar that shows if a site exposes web
          feeds.
        </li>
        <li>
          It makes unstyled RSS feeds readable; turning the absolute mess from
          before into a more pleasant preview:
        </li>
      </ul>

      <figure>
        <img
          src="/images/blog/rss-fancy.png"
          alt="A pretty rendered RSS feed with suybscribe button" />
        <figcaption>Phew, that's better.</figcaption>
      </figure>
      
      <p> It's <a href="//addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/hotfox-for-rss/"> available in the Mozilla Add-ons store</a >, if you'd like to try it. </p>  
        
      <details>
        <summary>FAQ</summary>

        <dl>
          <dt>Why the name?</dt>
          <dd>
            Fire is hot; idk it just sounded cool. There's not really a reason.
          </dd>

          <dt>
            Why build a new extension when
            <a href="//addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/rsspreview/">
              it</a
            >
            <a href="//addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/awesome-rss/">
              already</a
            >
            <a href="//addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/want-my-rss/">
              exists</a
            >?
          </dt>
          <dd>
            Because this seemed like a fun project to learn something about
            developing browser extensions.
          </dd>

          <dt>Will there be a Chrome version?</dt>
          <dd>
            No. I don't use Chrome myself;
            <a
              href="//blog.geheimesite.nl/2021/12/google-chromium-en-een-monocultuur-op.html">
              I don't like Google's attitude</a
            >.<br />
            But kudos to them—they
            <a
              href="//www.ghacks.net/2022/08/22/google-chrome-is-getting-an-rss-feed-reader-on-desktop/">
              got it built in.
            </a>
          </dd>

          <dt>Where can I get it?</dt>
          <dd>
            On the
            <a href="//addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/hotfox-for-rss/">
              Mozilla Add-ons store</a
            >.
          </dd>
        </dl>
      </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In favor of the small</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/sources</link>
      <pubDate>18 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/sources</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p> What makes a reliable source? Since the internet went mainstream in the 90s, information has been readily available for everyone. But can it be trusted? At school, people seem to think 'the bigger the better'. Big sites are generally considered trustworthy, while small and relatively unknown sites, like personal blogs or forums, are off-limits. However, imho small blogs are typically better sources than those big news outlets. </p>  <p> For one, random people online usually don't have any financial incentives. They're not writing to please an advertiser, publisher or particular audience—they're writing because they're passionate about the subject. This makes a huge difference. There's no money at stake, no undisclosed incentives, no monetary gain. They don't need to clickbait their writing; there's no reason to maximize views. A blogger isn't financially dependent on their blog, so there's no goal to sell ads. They don't <em>need anything</em> from their readers. </p>  <p> Furthermore, the articles on credible news sites are generally written by journalists. That's good, because they fact-check and remain objective and neutral. However, a journalist will always be a generalist: they know a little about a lot. On the other hand, bloggers can be specialists and will often have a more in-depth understanding of the topic. In other words: specialized blogs are often more accurate than media coverage on the same subject. Just read some news items on <a href="//rubenerd.com/erwin-knolls-law-of-media-accuracy/" >topics you're familiar with yourself</a >: </p>  <blockquote cite="//rubenerd.com/erwin-knolls-law-of-media-accuracy/"> <p> I've mentioned a few times how easy it is to pick apart inaccuracies in media coverage on a topic you know about, and the unease that sets in when you realise every topic likely has the same issues. </p> </blockquote>  <p> Moreover, bloggers don't have any restrictions while writing: they can make their articles as long, technical, and detailed as they please, not having to tailor them to a specific audience. However, a journalist has to make their writing accessible to a large audience, exchanging valuable detail for readability. </p>  <p> On blogs and forums, I know that what I'm reading is the authentic and personal experience of an actual person — not some corporate marketing bullshit. I'm not alone in this btw; there's a reason people <a href="//dkb.blog/p/google-search-is-dying" >keep appending "reddit" to the end of their searches</a >. Small blogs are written by <em>people</em>. I think that scares institutions like schools, which were created in a world where the only other big institutions, like media companies and publishers, had the ability to put stuff into the world. "Oh no, actual people are now able to write and publish stuff on their own!" PANIC! </p>  <p> I think that we should be more kind towards stuff written by people. It's not scary; it's just different. </p>  <details> <summary>Clarification</summary> <p> The blogs I talk about here are not the commercial BuzzFeed kind of blogs, but rather the things you'd find on the <a href="//indieweb.org">IndieWeb</a> or <a href="//neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/">Small</a> <a href="//www.marginalia.nu/marginalia-search/about/">Web</a>. </p> </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Defaults</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/defaults</link>
      <pubDate>15 Mar 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/defaults</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Most documents are written in Calibri or Arial, everyone uses Google,
        and links on the second page of Google are rarely seen.
        <a
          href="https://archive.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/09/14/do-users-change-their-settings/"
          >Only 5% of users actually change the settings</a
        >.
      </p>

      <p>
        This is the
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_effect">Default Effect</a
        >—people don't change the defaults. Therefore, whatever ships
        with your product, that’s what most users will use. But why?
      </p>

      <p>
        It comes down to
        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_fatigue"
          >decision fatigue</a
        >, a psychological phenomenon in which a person's ability to make
        decisions deteriorates after making many decisions. Constantly making
        decisions is exhausting. Thus, when people are faced with multiple
        choices, they tend to stick to the default ones.
      </p>

      <blockquote
        cite="//bootcamp.uxdesign.cc/why-default-settings-matter-more-than-you-think-97af8c785edf">
        <p>
          People change the defaults if the effort required to change them feels
          less than the annoyance of sticking with them.
        </p>
      </blockquote>

      <!--Settings are complicated--and scary. The defaults work. Modifying them only poses the risk of breaking *something somewhere*, with no clue how to fix it.-->

      <p>
        Furthermore, users assume us programmers to know better. And frankly, we
        should. Just because we nerds like to play around with the settings
        doesn't mean everyone does. And it shouldn't be necessary either. Thus, the takeaway is: provide good defaults.
      </p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing {du}punkto</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/dupunkto</link>
      <pubDate>18 Feb 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/dupunkto</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Last year, I posted
        <a href="//classic.geheimesite.nl/v/18/thinking-about-tilde">
          my thoughts on running a tilde/pubnix</a
        >. In a nutshell, I wanted to experiment with setting up a small tilde, to
        learn more about Linux and the internet. And after a few months of
        experimenting, I finally have a system that I'm happy with. So today I'm
        introducing <a href="//dupunkto.org">{du}punkto</a>, my attempt at
        building <em>something</em>.
      </p>

      <p>
        In short, {du}punkto is a small group of like-minded people who are
        sharing a VPS. Everyone has access to the server over SSH or Mosh (handy
        for areas with wonky connections). The goal is to learn new things about
        *NIX systems, collaborate on code, experiment, and, above all, have fun.
        I'm co-maintaining it with
        <a href="//dupunkto.org/~msb">MSB</a>, one of my best friends. The
        website isn't finished yet, but it has a little more info, if you're
        curious.
      </p>

      <p>
        Our server is named <code>du11</code>, after my web server
        <code>s11</code>, and it's running FreeBSD 13. I opted for BSD because I
        like the tidy and organized folder structure, large repos, and jails
        functionality. It's running a bunch of services for developing and
        collaborating on software. Most notably:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>
          Web hosting for every Unix user via a <code>public_html</code> folder
          in their home directory.
        </li>
        <li>
          A Gitolite server with a cgit web frontend and mirroring to GitHub and
          Codeberg.
        </li>
        <li>FTP storage with a web portal.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>
        It's also possible to run complimentary services in FreeBSD jails, like:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>A CardDAV and CalDAV server for me and my girlfriend.</li>
        <li>A Miniflux instance for personal use.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>
        I'm very excited about it. I'm looking forward to seeing what we're
        gonna do with it further.
      </p>

      <details>
        <summary>Future plans</summary>

        <ul>
          <li>A handwritten classic Minecraft server.</li>
          <li>
            Gopher and Gemini hosting, using <code>public_gem</code> and
            <code>public_gopher</code> respectively.
          </li>
          <li>
            A VSCode server, similar to <a href="//vscode.dev">vscode.dev</a>.
          </li>
          <li>A Matrix homeserver with Whatsapp bridging.</li>
          <li>A Mastodon or Lemmy instance?</li>
        </ul>
      </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Movies and Limited Series</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/good-movies</link>
      <pubDate>07 Feb 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/good-movies</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>So lately I've been watching a lot of Netflix.</p>

      <p>
        Generally I'm not the kind of person that consumes a lot of media. I'd
        rather make things; I find creating things way more satisfying.
      </p>

      <p>
        However, I got a bit burned out in terms of ideas — I didn't know what
        to build — enery, and time (school am I right ✨). So, instead I spent
        about 20 hours of my life staring at a screen, looking at fictional
        characters living their almost perfect made-up lives.
      </p>

      <p>Anyways, I really enjoyed these in particular:</p>

      <ul>
        <li>After</li>
        <li>Tick, tick… BOOM!</li>
        <li>Heartstopper</li>
        <li>Inventing Anna</li>
        <li>Bohemian Rhapsody</li>
        <li>Love, Rosie</li>
        <li>Friends with Benefits</li>
        <li>Lady Chatterley's Lover</li>
        <li>The Girl Nextdoor</li>
        <li>Queen's Gambit</li>
        <li>Don't Look Up</li>
        <li>Dirty Lines</li>
        <li>The Social Network</li>
        <li>The Playlist</li>
        <li>The Social Dilemma</li>
        <li>Yesterday</li>
        <li>I Used to Be Famous</li>
        <li>We Are the Wave</li>
      </ul>

      <p>
        I really enjoyed the mini series in particular; it allows the filmmaker
        to tell a more detailed story, yet it doesn't require as much time (and
        commitment) to watch, opposed to, forexample, a 7-season-long show.
      </p>

      <p>
        A movie feels short when you're used to a series. But that's part of the
        appeal I think. A movie doesn't try to suck you in, like a series does.
        It just tells a story.
      </p>

      <details>
        <summary>Context</summary>
        <p>
          I wrote this a while back (somewhere fall last year), but I forgot to
          publish it. I found the draft yesterday.
        </p>

        <p>
          Also, a lot of movies listed above share one common theme: they're all
          semi-related to the reproductive system; I'm a teenager, after all ;)
        </p>
      </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of generative AI in writing</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/gpt</link>
      <pubDate>23 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/gpt</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Since its introduction a little more than a year ago, we've been
        discussing ChatGPT a lot at school. It's an interesting topic, for sure.
        How can it be used in school? By students or teachers? Is using AI
        cheating? Will it interfere with the development of writing skills or
        help? Should it be used at all?
      </p>
      <p>
        Generally, we seem to have the urge to ban upcoming technologies that
        radically change things. Indeed, I've repeatedly heard people call to
        ban use of generative AI, calling it plagiarism and fraud. However, like
        everything, the matter is more nuanced than seems to be the case at
        first sight. Even if we were to completely ban generative AI, enforcing
        a ban like that will prove harder and harder the further models like GPT
        evolve. Besides, it probably won't restrain students from using models
        like them. Therefore, we should think about and discuss how we could
        properly integrate AI models into our writing.
      </p>
      <p>
        With that in mind, here are some of the primary takeaways after using
        ChatGPT on-and-off for about a year.
      </p>
      <p>
        ChatGPT is—mistakenly—mainly used to <em>generate</em> prose. However,
        the prose it generates is mediocre; it's dull and repetitive.
        Moreover,—even tho OpenAI tries to prevent it—the model hallucinates
        fairly often. This means nothing it generates can be trusted to be
        factually correct.
      </p>
      <p>
        Instead, it is way more powerful as a tool to edit and transform
        language. As Linus wrote a while back:
      </p>
      <blockquote cite="https://thesephist.com/posts/latent/">
        <p>
          Not "computers can complete text prompts, now what?" but "computers
          can understand language, now what?"
        </p>
      </blockquote>
      <p>
        The AI models are unable to understand what they are writing about.
        They're only selecting words that sound plausible given the context of
        their training data and the prompt. But they do know grammar, spelling,
        and essay structure. That's where their strength lies. Not the ability
        to generate okay-sounding essays, but their ability to understand and
        transform language. Use it to your advantage.
      </p>
      <p>
        Instead of prompting "can you generate an argumentative essay on the
        role of religion in public schools", we should prompt things like "can
        you rewrite this paragraph to be more academic" or "can you show me
        alternatives to this sentence".
      </p>
      <p>
        ChatGPT and similar models are not a threat to writing. Instead, they
        are merely new tools that can—if utilized correctly—further improve our
        writing. The impact they will have is purely defined by how we use them.
      </p>

      <p>
        <small>
          *this post was written by me, but edited and
          <a href="//languagetool.org">checked for grammar mistakes</a> using
          AI.
        </small>
      </p>

      <details>
        <summary>Extras</summary>
        <p>Some additional notes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            LLMs are best used in combination with existing tools, like
            <a href="//jsomers.net/blog/dictionary">a good dictionary</a>,
            thesaurus, and spell checkers.
          </li>
          <li>
            It's really a bit silly to call this category of AI "generative",
            because (in my opinion) that's the thing they're worst at.
          </li>
          <li>
            While not really related to this topic, the
            <a href="//thesephist.com/posts/latent/"
              >post I quoted from Linus</a
            >
            is great and you should definitely read it!
          </li>
        </ul>
      </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop saying "users" and "content"</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/stupid-terminology</link>
      <pubDate>15 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/stupid-terminology</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Terminology like <em>users</em> and <em>content</em> is demeaning and
        hurtful.
      </p>
      <p>
        Artists aren't creating <em>content</em> to populate our
        datasets—they're creating movies, music, essays, drawings, games,
        paintings. Labeling a work that someone created, out of passion and
        love, <em>content</em>, is frankly disrespectful. It reduces the
        creative work from something beautiful to merely another piece of
        <em>content</em>, and greatly undervalues the effort and skill necessary
        to create it.
      </p>
      <p>
        Likewise, calling people <em>users</em>, dehumanizes them. It turns them
        into a mere datapoint, or worse, an asset to be exploited.
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          There are only two industries that call their customers "users":
          illegal drugs and software.
        </p>

        —<cite>Edward Tufte</cite>
      </blockquote>

      <p>We should stop using these terms; they're stupid.</p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Banning phones is not solving anything</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/symptom-relief</link>
      <pubDate>14 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/symptom-relief</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        Terminology like <em>users</em> and <em>content</em> is demeaning and
        hurtful.
      </p>
      <p>
        Artists aren't creating <em>content</em> to populate our
        datasets—they're creating movies, music, essays, drawings, games,
        paintings. Labeling a work that someone created, out of passion and
        love, <em>content</em>, is frankly disrespectful. It reduces the
        creative work from something beautiful to merely another piece of
        <em>content</em>, and greatly undervalues the effort and skill necessary
        to create it.
      </p>
      <p>
        Likewise, calling people <em>users</em>, dehumanizes them. It turns them
        into a mere datapoint, or worse, an asset to be exploited.
      </p>
      <blockquote>
        <p>
          There are only two industries that call their customers "users":<br />
          illegal drugs and software.
        </p>

        —<cite>Edward Tufte</cite>
      </blockquote>

      <p>
        Terms like these shift focus away from the humans in the equation.
        Language is the lense through which we see the world. Use it wisely.
      </p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the mobile phone ban</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones-banned</link>
      <pubDate>08 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones-banned</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[
      <p>
        Last month the Dutch government announced that from next year on mobile
        phones will be banned in high school. As a student who is currently in
        high school, I think it's a fundamentally good development, but the
        media attention around it just feels wrong.
      </p>

      <p>
        The news is full of items of cherry-picked comments from teenagers who
        feel "relieved" because they "finally talk to each other". But also
        teenagers who are sad because "they won't have any memories of high
        school if they can't take photos". They present a greatly exaggerated
        story praising this measure the government imposed to protect the youth
        against themselves.
      </p>

      <p>
        It's all so over the top. Contrary to popular belief, teenagers
        <em>do</em> talk to each other, even in the presence of a mobile phone.
        In breaks, we play card games like Uno and Bullshit. We read books. We
        complain about how stupid school and homework is. You know, normal
        stuff. And our phones have a place too. Sometimes we play mobile games
        in the break, like
        <a href="//www.evilapples.com" target="_blank">Evil Apples</a> or
        <a href="//garticphone.com/" target="_blank">Gartic Phone</a>. But
        that's still something we do <em>together</em>.
      </p>

      <p>
        And, yes, phones are distracting. Yes, they cause mayhem from time to
        time. Yes, social media is shit. I am very much aware. But all of that
        is also true for adults. These devices and the apps on them are made to
        be extremely addictive, it's their fucking business model. It's not just
        teenagers who get addicted. And it's certainly not our fault that we get
        addicted. Even the people who built these apps in the first place, who
        know exactly how they work and what tricks are used to exploit our
        psychology, they still
        <a href="//thesocialdilemma.com">aren't able to restrain themselves</a>.
        Adults aren't magically immune.
      </p>

      <p>
        It feels like it's a bunch of grey birds going "kids these days...",
        "you can't get off your phones, and now we're going to take them away",
        "it's for your own good!" and then continuing to celebrate on social
        media. Hypocrisy at its peak.
      </p>

      <p>
        So yes, I think it's great that phones have been banned in high schools.
        The next step would be everywhere else (and especially the parlement).
      </p>

      <details>
        <summary>Extras</summary>
        <p>Some other notes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            <p>
              Schools spent years digitizing everything. Schedules, grades,
              homework, study materials and more are now all exclusively
              available in web applications. They made this move with the
              assumption that these platforms would always be accessible for
              students via their mobile phone (a wrong assumption by the way,
              because this excludes students like myself that would rather leave
              their phone at home). How are schools going to deal with this?
            </p>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>
              How are schools going to enforce this? They've been burdened with
              enough additional administrative tasks already. And what even
              counts as a mobile phone?
              <del
                >Do all mobile devices count? What about my iPad? Or an old iPod
                Touch? My DIY Raspberry Pi Zero project with a rectangular touch
                screen? And what if it were a square instead? And what about
                smartwatches? They can TikTok too. Does every portable device
                with an internet connection fall under this new law?</del
              >
            </p>
            <p>
              <ins
                >Update: I read the law on rijksoverheid.nl and they include
                "smartphones", "tablets", and "smartwatches". <em>However</em>,
                they do not provide a definition for these terms.
                Disappointing.</ins
              >
            </p>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </details> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phones, assumptions and expectations</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones</link>
      <pubDate>29 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/phones</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[
      <p>
        I'm 16 years old. I strongly dislike my phone. You never thought you'd
        ever hear those two sentences from the same person, did you?
      </p>

      <p>
        I started feeling like this a few years back. My parents decided I
        couldn't charge my phone at night, and consequently my phone died a lot
        during the day. After a while, I stopped missing it. Even if I have it
        with me, I don't use it anymore.
        <a href="//blog.geheimesite.nl/2022/03/een-maand-zonder-telefoon.html"
          >Last year, I challenged myself to put away my phone for a month</a
        >, and my primary conclusion was that most inconvience caused by not
        having a phone, is imposed by the expectations and assumptions of other
        people.
      </p>

      <p>
        I hate the fact that I'm expected to always be available for everyone.
        All it takes is one tap: <i>ping</i>. It's annoying. Every time I'm
        trying to actually get something done, my phone just keeps going
        <i>beep boop ping pong</i>. It's like someone is tapping my shoulder
        every few minutes. "Can I have your attention please?" My concentration
        is already severly fractured. I don't want to know that you've tagged
        me, I don't feel like sending selfies back and forth and I don't care
        that some artist released a new album.
        <em>I just want to get my shit done</em>.
      </p>

      <p>
        Phones are supposed to be tools. Tools should never, ever,
        <em>ever</em>, have control over us. We're supposed to be the master of
        our tools, not the other way around.
      </p>

      <p>
        That's easily solved tho. My phone is always on silent. However, people
        still <em>expect</em> me read and reply instantly. That's what bothers
        me: the fucking social pressure to participate.
      </p>

      <p>
        Furthermore, everyone assumes you to have and always carry a phone with
        you. Oh yes,
        <em>let's do a Kahoot</em>! Or some other activity requiring a phone. Or
        <em>just scan this QR code and you'll be done</em>. Or how about we put
        the schedule on a mobile app? You'll need a smartphone to get a DigiD
        too, which is needed to access your medical records, apply for vaccines,
        and pay your taxes. Sooner or later you'll need to setup mobile banking
        as well, because the device we use for signing into the online banking
        portal doesn't have replaceable batteries and we won't give you a
        replacement when it eventually dies.
      </p>

      <p>
        It's the small things, the assumptions and expectations.<br />
        And it's so annoying.
      </p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/the-beginning</link>
      <pubDate>09 Nov 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/the-beginning</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>
        The dawn of the universe is a paradox. There are two ways to explain it:
      </p>

      <ul>
        <li>
          <p>
            The universe has a beginning. Something initiated the universe,
            which raises the question: how did that thing get there? And if
            there was no thing—the universe sprung from nothing—how can all be
            made from none?
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            The universe has no beginning—it has always existed in some form or
            capacity. This seems contradictory: how can everything exist
            forever? All this <em>stuff</em> must come from somewhere, right?
          </p>
        </li>
      </ul>

      <p>
        Saying you know the truth of the origin of the universe is lying to
        yourself. Nobody knows — and nobody will ever know. We simply can't
        grasp the very beginning, it's too contradictory. It's
        all-encompassing—too immense for a single human being to fathom.
      </p>

      <p>
        We must learn to live with the fact that we might never know the truth
        to some things. And I know, that's hard. It means letting go of the
        little grip we have on reality. But ultimately, it's the only real
        answer we have.
        <em>We don't know, and that's okay.</em>
      </p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://roblog.nl/blog/introduction</link>
      <pubDate>15 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://roblog.nl/blog/introduction</guid>
      <content:encoded> <![CDATA[ <p>Hi. So, you stumbled upon my blog, cool.</p>

      <p>
        I'm a random teenager from the Netherlands, and this is my little corner
        of the internet.
      </p>

      <p>
        I post little notes about my life here. I made this site because I love
        minimalism and the initial idea of the web: a giant library of
        knowledge. This is my lil' corner of that library; as lightweight and
        simple as it can get. I'm not trying to scream, I'm just looking talk.
      </p>

      <p>
        This blog is mostly for myself, but you can read along if you're
        inclined. I'm planning to do mostly long-form casual writing. For now
        posts will be published exclusively on the Web, but I'm looking into
        Gemini and Gopher hosting.
      </p>

      <p>I'm really bad at these “welcome!!” kind of posts. Sowwy!</p> ]]> </content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>